# ABRAHAM COLEMAN

#### Software Developer

# **ABOUT ME**

I graduated from the University of Northern Iowa in the spring of 2015, with a degree in Computer Science. The University of Northern Iowa introduced me to Drupal in 2013. I was among the top of the class when the Drupal course ended, and built several different websites for Northern Iowa using the Drupal 7 platform. After graduation and various internships, I moved on to the University of Nebraska. My time there was immensely important, as my mentors taught me many of the intricacies of development, accessibility, and validation. After that, moving to Nelnet allowed me to spread my wings as a developer, and I was able to own several large development projects. My time here at Creighton as a Web Developer has been truly rewarding, and the other developers have been outstanding team members.

#### CONTACT

# 14009 Tregaron Ridge Court #6 Bellevue, Nebraska 68123

**t**: 402-800-5515 e: abraham@abaracus.com w: www.abaracus.com



in https://www.linkedin.com/in/abaracus

# **EXPERIENCE**

#### Software Developer | Creighton University

2019 - Present

Part of the Web Development team working on Creighton University's Drupal 7 & 8 platforms. Develop applications and adapt existing applications to operate more efficiently. Gather and receive requirements and develop moderately complex solutions that includes automated testing procedures. Work with the Operations team to ensure smooth transition to production support teams. Work within the ITIL framework and Agile development methodologies.

#### Web Strategist | Creighton University

Work with the Marketing and Communication website team to develop, launch and maintain websites on the gradschool.creighton.edu and adultdegrees.creighton.edu platforms. Work closely with the Graduate and Adult Marketing office to ensure that web strategy aligns with Graduate and Adult enrollment priorities and goals.

#### Web Designer/Developer | Nelnet Business Solutions

2017 - 2018

Collaborated with the Content Management Team to design, develop, and refresh website for Content Management System. Implemented look and feel decisions utilizing JavaScript, HTML 5 and CSS. Protected site content by designing, implementing and adhering to security standards for website development and/or procedures.

#### Front-End Web Developer | University of Nebraska

Was responsible for the front-end web development of Academic Services and Enrollment Management digital marketing initiatives. Worked closely with the Web Design Coordinator to implement site design and translate it to standards-compliant, cross-browser markup and styles. Also was responsible for ensuring the Academic Services and Enrollment Management websites meet current accessibility requirements.

## **EDUCATION**

#### University of Northern Iowa

2011 - 2015

Bachelor's Degree in Computer Science Dean's List 2014-2015

## INVOLVEMENT

## Member

Professional Development Committee University of Nebraska 2016 - 2017

#### Member

Grafx Club University of Northern Iowa 2014 - 2015

#### Vice President

Cedar Valley Linux Users University of Northern Iowa 2014 - 2015

#### SKILLS

Photoshop/Illustrator InDesign Dreamweaver Visual Studio HTMI CSS/SASS Barebones JavaScript Content Management Systems Bootstrap Drupal Version Control/Git Responsive Design W3C Validation SEO